Long ago, Inazuma had five legendary poets
Uzun zaman önce Inazuma'da beş efsanevi ozan vardı.
People bestowed upon them the title of The Five Kasen
İnsanlar onlara Beş Kasen unvanını uygun görmüştü.
One Year
Bir yıl
The poet Suikou made his way to Tenshukaku
ozan Suikou, Tenshukaku'ya doğru yola çıktı.
And presented the Kasen's work for the Shogun's perusal
Ve Kasen'in çalışmalarını, incelemesi için Şogun'a sundu.
But a page from the works of Aoi no Okina had been torn out
Fakat Aoi no Okina'nın eserinin bir parçası yırtılıp atılmıştı.
And Suikou was questioned regarding the matter
Suikou bununla ilgili sorgulandı.
Suikou pleaded guilty
Suikou suçunu itiraf etti.
He admitted to drinking at the tavern the night before
Bir gece önce handa içtiğini söyledi.
And vaguely recalled a mysterious figure approaching while he was intoxicated
Alkollü haldeyken gizemli birinin yaklaştığını hayal meyal hatırlıyordu.
That figure was none other than Aoi no Okina himself
Bu biri Aoi no Okina'nın ta kendisiydi.
This turn of events had begun with an unnamed individual
Bu olaylar isimsiz bir kişi ile başlamıştı.
Under whose coercion Aoi no Okina was forced
Bu kişinin zorlamasıyla Aoi no Okina
He knew nothing
Bu kişinin asıl niyetinden
All he knew was that
Tek bildiği
The poem had to do with an old acquaintance, Akahito
şiirin eski tanıdığı Akahito ile ilgili olduğuydu.
Akahito had once belonged to the Five Kasen
Akahito bir zamanlar Beş Kasen'in bir üyesiydi.
Each poem he composed, he marked with a scarlet red seal
Yazdığı her şiiri parlak kızıl bir mühürle işaretlerdi.
Hence the "Aka" in his name
Bu nedenle adında "Aka" vardı.
Such a distinguished writer was he
Böylesine seçkin bir yazardı.
And yet one of the poems he had submitted the previous year
Fakat önceki yıl gönderdiği şiirlerden biri
Was found to be plagiarized
bir başkasından çalıntıydı.
Akahito was exiled for his crimes
Akahito suçlarından dolayı sürgün edildi.
And only four of the Five Kasen remained
Böylece Beş Kasen'den dördü kaldı.
Sumizome went over Akahito's poems
Sumizome, Akahito'nun şiirlerini inceledi.
And noticed that the plagiarized poem lacked his seal
Ve çalıntı şiirde mühür olmadığını fark etti.
She immersed his poetry in a stream nearby
Şiirini yakındaki bir nehre batırdı.
And only on the plagiarized poem
Sadece çalıntı şiirin
Did the ink run
mürekkebi aktı.
Aoi no Okina passed by
Aoi no Okina oradan geçiyordu.
And witnessed Sumizome's doing
Ve Sumizome'nin yaptıklarına tanık oldu.
Which he then recorded in a poem
Ardından olanları bir şiire döktü.
Thus transpired the events of Suikou's poetry submission
İşte Suikou'nun şiirlerini gönderme süreci böyle gerçekleşti.
And this is where the story comes to an end
Ve hikaye burada sona eriyor.